{
    "id": "d87f606e6ccf4562b0a821905c4c1c04",
    "title": "Past Or Present Perfect Tense Exercise",
    "exercises": [
        {
            "id": "08842a380fcb4e2db708451a56194d0a",
            "title": "Past Or Present Perfect Tense",
            "questions": [
                {
                    "question": "He .................. all his childhood in a quaint village in China.",
                    "description": "We use the simple past tense to talk about finished longer situations in the past.",
                    "answers": [
                        "spent",
                        "has spent",
                        "was spending"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "I ...................... all day yesterday.",
                    "description": "We use the past continuous tense to stress that an activity was in progress at every moment during a period of time.",
                    "answers": [
                        "have read",
                        "was reading",
                        "have been reading"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "Mozart died while he ..................... the Requiem.",
                    "description": "The past continuous is often used with the simple past tense. In this case, the past continuous usually refers to a longer background action.",
                    "answers": [
                        "composed",
                        "was composing",
                        "has composed"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "I ..................... the cleaning. What shall I do now?",
                    "description": "We use perfect tenses to indicate completion.",
                    "answers": [
                        "did",
                        "have done",
                        "am doing"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "I ................... in India for ten years when I was a child.",
                    "description": "We use the simple past to talk about longer situations in the past.",
                    "answers": [
                        "lived",
                        "have lived",
                        "was living"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "I canâ€™t play tomorrow because I ................. my leg.",
                    "description": "We use the present perfect tense to say that a finished action is connected with the present in some way.",
                    "answers": [
                        "broke",
                        "have broken",
                        "had broken"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "My puppy ....................",
                    "description": "My puppy is dead now. We use the present perfect tense to say that a finished action is connected with the present in some way.",
                    "answers": [
                        "died",
                        "has died",
                        "dies"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "I ................... a lot in Asia and Africa.",
                    "description": "The present perfect tense is often used to express the idea of completion or achievement.",
                    "answers": [
                        "traveled",
                        "have traveled",
                        "am traveled"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "Once upon a time there .................... a beautiful princess.",
                    "description": "The present perfect tense is not used in story-telling.",
                    "answers": [
                        "has lived",
                        "have lived",
                        "lived"
                    ],
                    "correct": 2
                },
                {
                    "question": "He .................... hard for years.",
                    "description": "The present perfect is commonly used with the time expressions since and for.",
                    "answers": [
                        "worked",
                        "was working",
                        "has worked"
                    ],
                    "correct": 2
                },
                {
                    "question": "....................... Romeo and Juliet on TV last night?",
                    "description": "We cannot use the present perfect tense with time expressions referring to the past.",
                    "answers": [
                        "Did you see",
                        "Were you seeing",
                        "Have you seen"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "My late grandfather ................. a lot for me.",
                    "description": "We do not use the present perfect when we are thinking of a particular finished time, even if we do not mention it. Grandfather is no longer alive, so obviously the reference is to the past. \r\n",
                    "answers": [
                        "has done",
                        "did",
                        "Either could be used here"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                }
            ]
        }
    ]
}